Guide to the George Champion Papers, 1925-2019, MS 3241
New-York Historical Society
- Newspaper clippings, 1983-2019, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  • "Second Largest Bank Picks Ex-San Diegan" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Speaker—George Champion.. ." [unidentified, undated newspaper]
  • "Thinking Straight About Our Society & Our Economy" [unidentified, undated newspaper]
- Opportunities Industrialization Center, 1967-1970, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, meeting minutes, budget proposals, etc.
- Oral history interview transcripts, 1978 July 7, 12 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
  • George Champion | Oral History Interview | July 7, 1978 | July 12, 1978 | Linda Edgerly, Interviewer | The Chase Manhattan Archives [copy 1; single sided].
  • George Champion | Oral History Interview | July 7, 1978 | July 12, 1978 | Linda Edgerly, Interviewer | The Chase Manhattan Archives [copy 2; double sided].
- Periodical articles—about George Champion, 1952-2019, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  • Protestant Church Life, vol. 25, no. 21 (Feb. 16, 1952). Photograph of Champion, p. 1.
  • Sam B. Lyons, "Chase Manhattan is Prime News Source," Finance, Jan. 15, 1957, 43–44.
  • "Champion is President, Rockefeller Vice Chairman of Chase Manhattan Bank," Mid-Continent Banker, Jan. 1957, 36.
  • Unserem Gast, nr. 1, jahrgang 7, Jan. 1 1958. [German publication with photographs of Champion on p. 18.]
  • "Champion of the Chase. Billion Dollar Banker Branches Into New Services to Post Commanding Totals," Investor's Reader, vol. 32, no. 2 (Jan. 21, 1959). Profile of Champion, 25–30, with photograph on cover.
  • New Yorker cartoon of men stealing paintings from the Chase Manhattan Bank, Oct. 14, 1961.
  • Jack Craddock, "Portrait of a Banker: George Champion," American Banker, Oct. 5, 1962.
  • Protestant News. Articles reproduced from Oct. 27, 1962 issue of Protestant Church Life. Photograph of Champion, p. 1.
  • Charles J. V. Murphy, "Foreign Aid: Billions in Search of a Good Reason," Fortune, March 1963, 124–130, 205–206, 209–212.
  • "??The Lotos Club???," Lotos Leaf, March-April [1964], 22–24.
  • Dero A. Saunders, "Dartmouth's No. 1 Banker," Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, May 1964, 27–29.
  • John Berry, "The Banker in the News," Dun's Review and Modern Industry, Sep. 1965, 53–54. Profile and photograph of Champion.
  • "Stop, Look, Listen—Count Three," Newsweek, Oct. 18, 1965, 85–86.
  • Información gráfica Sobre la XIII Conferencia Monetaria de la ABA The American Bankers Association, Madrid—Granada, 1966. [Souvenir program, with calling card of Ramiro Suarez de Figeroa y Prieto.]
  • "Fed may lighten its touch," Business Week, Feb. 4, 1967, 29–30. Photograph of Champion, 29.
  • Winton M. Blount, "Businessmen urged to back tax-spending cuts bill," Washington Report, vol. 7, no. 22 (May 24, 1968).
  • "Training the 'Hard Core'—A Top Banker Tells His Story," U.S. News & World Report, Aug. 12, 1968, 51–52.
  • The J.O.B. Review, vol. 1, no. 1 (Aug. 1968). Photograph of Champion, p. 1.
  • Rudy Martinez, "A Man," The J.O.B. Review, vol. 1, no. 2 (Winter 1969). Profile and photograph of Champion, p. 1.
  • The 1926 Smoke Signals, April 1, 1969. Dartmouth alumni publication with Mention of Champion, 3–4.
  • John R. Coyne Jr., "Business to the Rescue," National Review, July 29, 1969, 744.
  • Footballetter: The National Football Foundation and Hall of Fame, vol. 12, no. 1 (Dec. 1969–Jan. 1970). Contains many photographs; probably includes Champion.
  • The Presbyterian Layman, vol. 4, no. 5 (May 1970). Photograph, p. 1, of "Planning Committee for Billy Graham New York Crusade June 24–28 in Shea Stadium. Seated: Fred Russell Esty, Committee Chairman, Billy Graham, Dr. Elmer Engstrom. Standing: George Champion and Dr. M. L. Wilson. Messrs. Esty and Champion also are Board members of the Presbyterian Lay Committee."
  • [Japanese publication], 1970.
  • "New York falls back on a rich resource," Business Week, Nov. 10, 1975, 83–88.
  • "Welcome to the town of Normal," dedication program, Normal City Hall-Police Complex, July 3, 1976. Contains brief biography of Champion, guest speaker.
  • Dero A. Saunders, "One vote for the old verities," Forbes, July 6, 1981.
  • "A banker's dissent," Forbes, Feb. 1, 1982.
  • Jay Rosenstein, "Veterans of Hard Times Advise Conservative Stance," American Banker: The Daily Financial Services Newspaper, Nov. 4, 1987, 1, 14.
  • Paul Craig Roberts, "What price bank reform?," The Washington Times, March 15, 1991.
  • Peter Grant and Robert McNatt, "Squandered Decade: How a Corporate Culture & A CEO's Reticence in the '80s Imperil Chase's Future," Crain's New York Business, June 17, 1991, 23-31.
  • Kelley Holland, "A Chastened Chase," Business Week, Sep. 26, 1994, 106-109.
  • [Robert Mateer, editor], "A Special Thank You," Christian Perspectives: A Journal of Free Enterprise, [1996].
  • "George Champion, 93, Head of Chase Manhattan in 1960's," The New York Times, Sep. 22, 1997.
  • Jeffrey Hart, "George Champion, R.I.P.," The Dartmouth Review, Oct. 15, 1997, 10.
  • Jeffrey Hart, "George Champion, R.I.P.," [1997] (www.angelfire.com/nh/emhi/hartonchamp.html).
  • Alex J. Pollock, "Heed a Banking Champion's Words on Loan Loss Reserves," May 8, 2012 (printout of article from unidentified website).
  • "Paging George Champion," Grant's Interest Rate Observer, vol. 34, no. 9 (May 6, 2016), 1–5, 8–10.
  • Alex J. Pollock, "The next crisis will come; Is your bank ready?," Sep. 1, 2016 (www.rstreet.org/op-ed/the-next-crisis-will-come-is-your-bank-ready/).
  • Grants, Dec. 13, 2019, 2. Mention of Champion.
  • Hugo Restall, "Hopkins Institute Reorganized," photocopy from an unidentified, undated newspaper.
  • Three pages from an unidentified, undated publication.
- Periodical articles—by George Champion, 1957-1996, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  • "Head of Chase Bank Expects Tight Money and High Interest to Continue for Some Time," Executives' Club News, vol. 33, no. 24 (March 29, 1957).
  • "Foreign Aid: A New Approach," Vital Speeches of the Day, vol. 29, no. 6 (Jan. 1, 1963), 177-180.
  • "With Impact More Striking Than Ever," Reader's Digest, vol. 84, no. 506 (June 1964).
  • "Why Politics is For You," reprinted from Nation's Business, March 1965.
  • "Government by Guideline: New Threat to Economic Freedom," Human Events, Aug. 7, 1965. [first page only]
  • "A Challenge to Business: Create Its Own 'Great Society'," reprinted from Reader's Digest, vol. 82, no. 532 (Aug. 1966), 107-110.
  • "Private Enterprise and Public Responsibility," Social Service Outlook, vol. 1, no. 4 (Sep. 1966), 7-11.
  • "Preaching What You Practice: A conversation with George Champion.. .," reprinted from Nation's Business, March 1967.
  • "Our Obsolete Welfare State," Human Events, Dec. 23, 1967, 812-813.
  • "Automation, Capital and Economic Growth," Dateline: Church & Industry in the Current Scene, vol. 12, no. 7 (April 1968), 5-6, 8.
  • "Puzzle for Next Administration—How to Halt Inflation," U.S. News & World Report, Nov. 11, 1968, 74-76.
  • "Inflation: Symptom of What Ails America," Monitor: The Voice of Industry in New York State—Since 1914, vol. 54, no. 4 (Nov.-Dec. 1968), 7-8, 23-24.
  • "The Round Table," The Nutmegger, May 1978.
  • "Thinking Straight About Our Society & Our Economy," Christian Perspectives: A Journal of Free Enterprise, vol. 9, no. 2 (Fall 1996), 3.
  • "Chase Manhattan's approach to multinational banking. A joint statement to multinational companies by Chairman Champion and President Rockefeller," Forbes, May 1, [year lacking].
  • "Will the Real America Please Stand Up?," [Reader's Digest?], undated.
- Personal, 1923-1972, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  Dartmouth College, 1923-1925
  • Blueprint of Dartmouth football "Defense—'23"
  • Program for "1926 Senior Class Smoker, Trophy Room, Dec. 1, 1925"
  • Pocket notebook with handwritten football signals, 1925
  George Champion (1840–1928) estate, 1928, 1935-1936, undated
  • Reproduction of advertisement for "Geo. Champion, Dealer in Hardware, Stoves, Tinware," The Oldest Hardware Store in Normal," "Established 1867," undated
  • Photocopies newspaper clippings from Bloomington, Illinois, on the death of George Champion (1840–1928)
  • Estate papers, 1935–1936
  Anecdotes, quotations, 1945, 1963, undated
  • Mimeographed letter from Lieut. Earle Bowles, USNR, Tokyo Bay, Japan, Sep. 2, 1945
  • "The Problem of Equality," sermon delivered by Dr. Walter R. Courtenay, First Presbyterian Church, Nashville, Sep. 15, 1963
  • Calligraphic sheet, "He who works with his hands is a laborer. / He who works with his hands and his mind is a craftsman. / He who works with his hands, his mind and his heart is an artist," undated
  • "A Father's Prayer.. .," "Reprinted with the gracious permission of Mrs. MacArthur," undated
  • Typed anecdotes, undated
  Chemical Bank loan papers, 1962–1967
  Miscellaneous, 1966–1972, undated
  • Letter from "Esther" to "Sally," July 20, 1966
  • Giko Unyu Company Ltd., Osaka, letter transmitting insurance certificate for goods shipped to Champion Dec. 1, 1967
  • Letter from George J. Gansel to Mary Conroy, secretary of George Champion, Feb. 19, 1972
  • Champion's social security card and accompanying documentation, undated
  • Chase National Bank stock receipt, undated
- Photographs, 1950-1969 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  • George Champion portrait (September 1950) [2 copies]
  • "Arrival at Augusta, Georgia from plane.. ." (1957 Spring).
  • "S.S. George Champion launched 3/22/58" (1958 March 22).
  • Rear Admiral J. D. Bulkeley portrait (1963 Dec. 10).
  • George Champion with Harry S. Truman and others (1964 Spring).
  • George Champion at New York Stock Exchange (1965 March 16).
  • George Champion with others (1966 Dec.).
  • George Champion at 1967 Annual CMB Golf Tournament (1967 Aug. 8).
  • George Champion receiving 1967 "Man-In-Management" Award (1968 Jan. 16).
  • George Champion receiving First Class Order of the Sacred Treasure from Government of Japan (1969 Oct. 7). [Seven images. See documentation (Box 1, Folder 4) and insignia (Box 4, Enclosure 1).]
  • George Champion at "Tribute of a Grateful Nation" ceremony with President and Mrs. Nixon, Mamie Eisenhower, and Herbert Brownell (1969 Oct. 14).
- Photographs, 1970-1993, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  • George Champion with Wally Shirra, Toots Shor, and Arnold Palmer [1970].
  • George Champion with Ikuo Yokota of the Nippon Kangyo Bank (1970 Oct. 14).
  • Hill Billies Camp, River Road, Bohemian Grove (1972 July).
  • George Champion portrait (1973 May).
  • George Champion at West Side Association of Commerce, Inc. 49th Annual Gold Medals Award Dinner, with Rev. Billy Graham and others (1973 Nov. 15).
  • George Champion at Football Dinner with Vice President Gerald Ford (1973 Dec. 4).
  • George Champion with family[?] (1977 July).
  • George Champion at Lotos Club with Norman Vincent Peale and others (1982 Nov. 8).
  • Foosland[?] Farm (1993 Fall).
  • George Champion at Economic Development Council meeting? (undated).
  • George Champion portraits (undated).
  • George and Eleanor Champion with others, including John F. Kennedy (undated).
  • Dwight D. Eisenhower portrait (undated).
- Photographs (oversize), 1961, 1963 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
  • George Champion with Chase Manhattan Bank board members[?] (1961) [2 copies, with a list of names identified in another photo which is not present].
  • George Champion with John F. Kennedy and others at Protestant Council of the City of New York dinner (1963 Nov. 8).
- Publications—40 For Presidents, 1976 November/December (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  40 For Presidents, year 1, book 6 (Nov./Dec. 1976). Contains Champion's "The City of New York... A Platform for Progress," pp. 52–55.
- Publications—Bankers Magazine, 1968, 1976 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
  • The Bankers Magazine, vol. 151, no. 3 (Summer 1968). Contains Champion's "Issues and Interpretations," pp. 9–10.
  • The Bankers Magazine, vol. 159, no. 3 (Summer 1976). Contains article by Champion, George Moore, and Arthur Roth, "Bank Elder Statesmen Look at Banking Today," pp. 17–21.
- Publications—Bankers Monthly, 1965 April 15 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  Bankers Monthly: National Magazine of Banking & Investments, vol. 82, no. 4 (April 15, 1965). Picture of Champion on cover.
- Publications—Chamber of Commerce, 1968 May (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
  Chamber of Commerce of the United States. The Business of Progress (May 1968). Contains Champion's "Progress Through the Application of Private Capital," pp. 11–13.
- Publications—Chase Manhattan, circa 1937, 1956-1971, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
  • The Chase Manhattan Magazine, vol. 3, no. 1 (March 1957).
  • The Chase Manhattan News, vol. 4, no. 10 (Oct. 1960).
  • The Chase Manhattan News, vol. 11, no. 1 (Jan. 1967).
  • The Chase Manhattan News, vol. 11, no. 4 (April 1967).
  • The Chase Manhattan News, vol. 12, no. 2 (Feb. 1968).
  • The Chase Manhattan News, vol. 12, no. 5 (May 1968).
  • The Chase Manhattan News, vol. 13, no. 2 (Feb. 1969). Includes The News Staff Annual Report.
  • The Chase Manhattan News, vol. 14, no. 6 (June 1970).
  • The Chase Manhattan News, vol. 15, no. 2 (Feb. 1971).
  • The Chase Manhattan News Special Supplement. The History of Chase Manhattan (April 1974?).
  • Stockholder News, Nov. 15, 1962.
  • The Chase Manhattan Bank Annual Report 1963.
  • The Chase Manhattan Bank. Report of the 1964 Annual Meeting of Stockholders [copy 1].
  • The Chase Manhattan Bank. Report of the 1964 Annual Meeting of Stockholders [copy 2 with attached press release dated Dec. 13, 1956].
  • The Chase Manhattan Bank NA Annual Report 1967.
  • Historical Summary of the Chase National Bank (circa 1937?).
- Publications—Current, 1963 January (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
  Current: The significant new material from all sources on the frontier problems of today, no. 33 (Jan. 1963). Contains Champion's "Mobilizing Private Capital," pp. 40-41.
- Publications—Dartmouth—football, 1925, 1963, 1999 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 18)
  • The Dartmouth Pictorial. Football Number, 1925.
  • Dartmouth's Undefeated Football Season '62 (1963).
  • Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, vol. 92, no. 4 (Dec. 1999).
- Publications—Economic Development Council of New York City, 1972-1979 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 19)
  • George Champion, The Forgotten Majority (Annual Meeting, Economic Development Council of New York City, Inc. and New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry, May 27, 1975).
  • George Champion, New York: On the Road to Recovery (Economic Development Council of New York City, 10th Annual Meeting, April 7, 1976). [With speeches by Walter B. Wriston and Robert S. Hatfield.]
  • George Champion, 1978: Year of Opportunity (Proceedings of the Semi-Annual Urban Affairs Meeting, Nov. 21, 1977). [With speeches by Walter B. Wriston and John E. Zuccotti.]
  • Accountability: Key to the Urban Future. 6th Annual Meeting Report (May 18, 1972).
  • Responsibility means Accountability. 7th Annual Meeting Report (May 22, 1973). [2 copies; copy 1 with tipped-in newspaper clipping "DAR Unit to Hear Former Banker Talk," undated.]
  • Business, the City, and the Future. 8th Annual Report (1973).
  • Business, the City, and the Crisis. 9th Annual Report (1974).
  • Management Continuity: Key to Strong City Government. 11th Annual Report [1975-1976?].
  • Managing New York City's demanding years ahead. 13th Annual Report (1978-1979).
  • [Memorandum] (Sep. 10, 1975).
  • Memorandum (Jan. 18, 1979).
  • Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Directors of [the] Economic Development Council of New York City, Inc. (Oct. 9, 1979).
  • Press release, "David Rockefeller Named Chairman of New York Chamber of Commerce and Economic Development Council" (Oct. 10, 1979).
  • Letter from Champion to "All Members and Friends of the Economic Development Council" (Oct. 18, 1979).
- Publications—Finance, 1957 January 15 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 20)
  Finance: All the News of the Hire of the Dollar, vol. 72, no. 1 (Jan. 15, 1957). Photograph of Champion on front cover.
- Publications—Forbes, 1961 October 1 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
  Forbes Business and Finance, vol. 88, no. 7 (Oct. 1, 1961). Cover photograph of "Chase Manhattan's Rockefeller & Champion."
- Publications—Nation's Business, 1967 March (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
  Nation's Business: A Useful Look Ahead, vol. 55, no. 3 (March 1967). Contains conversation with Champion, "Preaching What You Practice," pp. 49, 52-62.
- Publications—Newsweek, 1967 April 3 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
  Newsweek, vol. #, no. # (April 3, 1967). Cover photograph "David Rockefeller: New Era in Banking."
- Publications—New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
  • CCI Action, vol. 4, no. 15 (Dec. 30, 1976).
  • Action, vol. 1, no. 2 (June 3, 1977). Headline "Champion Urges Five Mayoral Platform Planks."
  • Action, vol. 1, no 7 (Nov. 4, 1977).
- Publications—Northwestern Banker, 1957 May (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
  Northwestern Banker, no. 838 (May 1957).
- Publications—Reader's Digest, 1966 August (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
  Reader's Digest, vol. 82, no. 532 (Aug. 1966). Contains Champion's "A Challenge to Business: Create Its Own 'Great Society'," pp. 107-110.
- Publications—Reserve City Bankers Bulletin, 1952-1960 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
  Bound volume containing (in reverse order)
  • Volume I (1952-1953)
  • Volume II (1953-1954)
  • Volume III (1954-1955)
  • Volume IV (1955-1956)
  • Volume V (1956-1957)
  • Volume VI (1957-1958)
  • Volume VII (1958-1959)
  • Volume VIII (1959-1960)
- Publications—The MBA: The Master in Business Administration, 1968 October (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
  The MBA: The Master in Business Administration, vol. 3, no. 1 (Oct. 1968). Contains Champion's "Our Moral Deficit," pp. 39–41.
- Publications—U.S. News & World Report, 1965-1971 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
  • U.S. News & World Report, vol. 58, no. 23 (June 7, 1965). Champion on p. 20, "A Top Banker Assails Government by Guideline."
  • U.S. News & World Report, vol. 65, no. 7 (Aug. 12, 1968). Champion on pp. 51-53, "Training the 'Hard-Core'—A Top Banker Tells His Story."
  • U.S. News & World Report, vol. 65, no. 20 (Nov. 11, 1968). Champion on pp. 74-76, "Puzzle for Next Administration—How to Halt Inflation."
  • U.S. News & World Report, vol. 70, no. 14 (April 5, 1971). Champion on pp. 49-50, 55, "From a Citizens' Panel on Defence; 'U.S. Superiority Has Ended'."
- Publications—by George Champion, 1945-1975 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 9)
  • Term Lending by Commercial Banks (Association of Reserve City Bankers, April 1945).
  • The Road Ahead for Banking (Illinois Bankers Association, St. Louis, Missouri, June 9, 1955).
  • The Challenge to the Dollar (Los Angeles Rotary Club, Jan. 30, 1959).
  • Asia and the United States: The Challenge They Share (The Economic Club of Detroit, May 23, 1960).
  • Taxes and the Government Debt: A Plan for the 'Sixties (State Bank Division, American Bankers Association Convention, San Francisco, Oct. 16, 1961).
  • A Report to the Members (New York Chamber of Commerce, Dec. 1962).
  • A New Approach to Foreign Aid (New York Chamber of Commerce, Dec. 4, 1962).
  • A Sound Investment for the Future (American Heart Association, after 1963).
  • Our Growing Responsibilities in a Changing World (Chamber of Commerce, Houston, Texas, Dec. 8, 1964).
  • What an Executive Should Know About His Political Responsibility (Dartnell Corporation, 1965).
  • Government-by-Guideline: A New Threat to Economic Freedom (Illinois Bankers Association, Chicago, May 25, 1965).
  • Private Enterprise and Public Responsibility in a Free Economy (18th Annual Business Conference, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J., March 24, 1966).
  • United States in the World Market Place: The Critical Years Ahead (John Hamilton Fulton Memorial Lectureship in the Liberal Arts, Middlebury College, April 24, 1967).
  • Inflation: A Symptom of What Ails America (1968).
  • Our Moral Deficit (11th Annual Good Friday Breakfast for Business and Professional Men, Los Angeles, April 12, 1968).
  • The Shifting Balance of Military Power (Sep. 30, 1970).
  • Help Wanted: Effective Management for New York City (43rd Annual Meeting, The Hundred Year Association of New York, Oct. 1, 1975).
- Speeches, 1955-1965 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 10)
  • Association of Reserve City Bankers (1959).
  • Your Stake in the Dollar (63rd Annual Convention of the Maryland Bankers Association, Atlantic City, N.J., May 11, 1959).
  • The Outlook for Money and Banking (Business Outlook Panel of the National Industrial Conference Board, New York City, May 21, 1959).
  • "Education and Free Enterprise—The Common Objective" (National Corporation Day Salute Dinner of the Independent College Funds of America, New York City, Oct. 10, 1960).
  • Taxes and the Government Debt: A Plan for the 'Sixties (State Bank Division at the American Bankers Association Convention, San Francisco, Oct. 16, 1961).
  • Freedom and Opportunity—Your Responsibility (Meeting of the Members' Council of the Commerce and Industry Association of New York, Inc., Feb. 27, 1962).
  • Freedom and Opportunity—Your Responsibility (Travelers Inner Circle, Travelers Insurance Company, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, July 27, 1962).
  • Remarks by George Champion, Chairman, The Chase Manhattan Bank (Panel on Taxation, Annual Meeting, United States Chamber of Commerce, Washington, D.C., April 30, 1963).
  • President's Message to Annual Meeting of Stockholders (July 11, 1963).
  • Address by George Champion, Chairman of the Board, The Chase Manhattan Bank (51st Anniversary Dinner of The Alfalfa Club, Washington, Jan. 25, 1964) [3 copies; copy 1 with emendations].
  • A Banker Looks at Dick Nixon (Lotus Club, New York, Feb. 27, 1964).
  • Let's "Get Involved" in Effective Citizenship (28th Annual Commencement Exercises, Stonier Graduate School of Banking, Rutgers—The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, June 19, 1964).
  • Government-By-Guideline: A New Threat to Economic Freedom (Illinois Bankers Association, Chicago, May 25, 1965).
  • Things I Have Learned Since Graduation (Commencement Exercises, Millikin University, Decatur, Illinois, June 6, 1965).
  • Communism's Economic Failures: The Lessons for the U.S. (Colorado Association of Commerce and Industry, Denver, Nov. 18, 1965).
- Speeches, 1966-1971 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 11)
  • The Worldwide Captial Shortage (International Investment Forum, London, Oct. 28, 1966).
  • Automation, Capital and Economic Growth (Annual Financial Conference, National Industrial Conference Board, New York, Feb. 16, 1967).
  • U.S. in the World Market Place: The Critical Years Ahead (John Hamilton Fulton Lecture, Middlebury College, Middlebury, Vermont, April 24, 1967).
  • Our Obsolete Welfare State (Grinnell College Convocation, Grinnell, Iowa, Oct. 29, 1967).
  • The Responsibilities of Leadership (Annual Man-in-Management Dinner, New York, Jan. 16, 1968).
  • Our Moral Deficit (11th Annual Good Friday Breakfast for Business and Professional Men, Los Angeles, April 12, 1968). [2 copies]
  • Progress Through the Application of Private Capital (56th Annual Meeting, U.S. Chamber of Commerce, Washington, April 29, 1968).
  • Wanted: A Realistic Approach to Foreign Aid (Annual Convention, Texas Bankers Association, San Antonio, May 13, 1968).
  • Inflation: A Symptom of What Ails America (American Mining Congress, Las Vegas, Nevada, Oct. 7, 1968). [Includes Champion's convention itinerary.]
  • The Changing Responsibilities of Management (Annual Meeting, American College of Hospital Administrators, Chicago, March 7, 1969).
  • Let's Be Economic Realists—But Let's Not Be Pessimists! (California Bankers Association, Los Angeles, May 27, 1969).